字幕後期：HDSky
瑪格利特
Margaret.
我究竟該拿這個怎麼辦
What the hell am I supposed to do with this?
這是醫囑哦 親愛的
Doctor's orders, honey.
無飽和脂肪攝入
No saturated fat.
女士 那是個蹩腳破醫生
Ma'am, that doctor is a hack.
而且他很沒用
And he's pathetic.
他甚至都不該拿到執業證
He shouldn't even have a license.
別再聽那個破醫生的啦
Stop listening to the doctor.
天哪
Jesus.
你讓我吃麵包
You give me bread?
第一 這不是烤的
First of all it's not toasted,
第二 這上頭抹的是
second of all it's peanut
沒摻一丁點果醬的花生
butter without any jam.
你想讓我怎麼吃 直接嚥下去
How do you expect me to swallow this or get it down?
天曉得 我得跟你說幾次啊
How many goddamn times do I have to tell you that?
別再看那破烹飪書了 好好學學怎麼做
Get your nose out of a cookbook and learn to make
花生醬和果醬三明治
a peanut butter and jelly sandwich.
再這麼說下去
Keep talking like that
你就自己去做你那三明治吧
and you'll be making your own sandwiches.
你說什麼
What did you say?
那是啥
What was that?
譯名: 美國暴力
*
據全球健康教育協會稱
According to the Global Health Education Consortium,
造成暴力的社會原因有很多
there are numerous social causes for violence.
貧窮 失業
Poverty, unemployment,
吸毒以及酗酒 文化準則
illicit drug and alcohol abuse, cultural norms.
但這些外部影響
But these external influences
並不是造成暴力的根本原因
don't explain the root cause of violence.
德克薩斯州起訴約翰遜
Texas versus Johnson.
埃德·約翰遜在他的前女友
Ed Johnson was charged with first degree murder
和她所拜訪的男孩的死後
after the deaths of his ex-girlfriend
被指控一級謀殺
and a boy she was seeing.
由於此罪性質極其惡劣
Because of the heinousness of the crimes,
以及受害人的年齡
and the ages of the victims,
公訴人想要法官判處他死刑
the prosecutors wanted to push for the death penalty.
但因為埃德差幾個月不滿18週歲
But because Ed was a few months shy of turning 18,
法官將其駁回
the judge balked.
在服刑僅僅五年後 他就因改過自新
He was released after sewing only five years,
被釋放
for good behavior.
假釋後一周
One week after being paroled,
埃德的車 在一次例行交通檢查中被攔停
Ed was pulled over for a routine traffic stop.
警方在他的後備箱裏發現了
And the police found the severed head
一個九歲小女孩被割下來的頭顱
of a nine year old little girl in his trunk.
由於這個新發現 埃德被判處死刑
Because of this new discovery, Ed was sentenced to death.
如果州政府在他第一次行兇後
Had the state sentenced him after the first violent act
在那兩條無辜的生命逝去後 就判處他
where two innocent lives were lost,
那個小女孩也就能逃過一劫
that little girl would've been spared.
更有意思的是 據其所訴
The most interesting part, is according to his records,
他並沒有精神病
there was no history of mental illness
或神經病史
or neurological diseases.
那麼他是天生暴力呢
So was he born violent?
自問一下
Ask yourself that.
現在 由於不清楚暴力產生的根源
Now, without understanding where violence originates,
幫助刑滿者 恢復正常生活就是不可能的
it's impossible to rehabilitate,
更別說阻止將來暴力行為的發生
let alone prevent future violent acts.
那如果說暴力在我們社會
Well what if violence is
我們美國文化中
so ingrained to our society,
-是如此根深蒂固 -抱歉先生
our American culture-- - Excuse me, sir.
以至於暴力的爆發是不可避免的呢
That outbursts are inevitable?
這無法避免
There's no escaping it.
我不願相信我們遠離
I refuse to believe that we're far from stopping
暴力在全國範圍席捲
the epidemic of violence sweeping through our country.
即使是在一個以殺人償命
Even with a system in place
的體系內
that just trades death for death?
好吧 那麼執行死刑也是暴力行為嗎
Okay, so are controlled executions an act of violence?
還是說是對愛著受害者的人 的仁慈行為
Or an act of mercy for the loved ones of the victims?
殺戮不總是暴力的嗎
Isn't the act of killing always violent?
難道是嗎
Is it?
我希望你們在接手案件時思考一下
I want you guys to think about that when you pick a case.
尋找隱藏的動機 以及遺漏的線索
Look for the hidden motives, and clues that were missed.
還有如果這些線索未被遺漏
And had they not been missed,
悲劇就能夠避免嗎
would the tragedy have been prevented?
記得要客觀公正
And remember to be objective.
那是對情況做出準確且
That is the key to get an accurate
公正的判斷的關鍵 好嗎
and impartial read on the situation, okay?
下課
Class dismissed.
-您是 -本·伍茲
And you are? - Ben Woods.
地方助理檢察官
Assistant District Attorney.
我想 咨詢你一個案件
I'd like for you to consult on a case for me.
他名叫傑克·謝伊
His name is Jack Shea,
72小時後他將被處死
he's set for execution in 72 hours.
由於今年是選舉年
With it being an election year,
政府頂著額外的壓力
the Governor's under extra pressure
要重新評估我州在死刑問題上的立場
to reevaluate the State's position on capital punishment.
法律條文的細微差別並不是我的專長
Well the nuances of the law aren't exactly my specialty--
我來此不是尋找法律意見的 小姐
I'm not here for legal advice, Miss--
-博士 -博士 抱歉
- Doctor. - Doctor, pardon.
現在你已看了新聞
Now you've watched the news,
民眾都在抗議
national focus was on the protests,
這已把州長逼到了絕境
it's got the Governor backed into a corner.
現在如果該判處繼續執行下去
Now if this execution goes forward,
按我們的時刻表 不摻雜官方評論
our schedule, without an official review,
州長 將不會有新一輪執政的機會
the Governor won't stand a chance of serving another term.
我只是想讓你跟他談談 好嗎
I just want you to talk to him, hmm?
給他專業的意見
Give him your professional opinion.
就當是盡你的公民義務了
Consider it your civic duty.
或許 僅僅是或許 你將拯救一條生命
Maybe, just maybe, you'll save a life.
我的名片和電話號碼在那裏面
My card and my number's in there.
嘿 快點動起來 格裏姆巴
Hey, quit monkeying around, Marimba.
或許是你該停止到處指揮了 利奧
Well maybe if you stopped lion around, Leo.
起床啦 懶漢 探險時間到
Get up, lazy bones, it's time for adventuring.
媽咪
Mommy!
嗨 寶貝閨女
Hi, baby girl.
你不該躺在床上
Shouldn't you be in bed?
外婆說 睡覺前我可以再看一個電視節目
Grandma said I could watch one more show on TV before bed.
她是說了 是吧
She did now, huh?
是啊 這個節目裏所有的動物
Yep, all the animals on this show
在動物園裏住在一起
live together at the zoo.
噢
Aw.
我們能去動物園嗎 媽咪
Can we go to the zoo, Mommy?
我跟你說吧
Well I tell you what.
你先上樓去刷牙
How about you go upstairs, brush your teeth,
整個星期都跟外婆乖乖的
and you be a good girl for Grandma all week,
然後下個週末我就帶你去 好嗎
and then I will take you next weekend, okay?
上樓去刷牙吧 我會給你掖好被子的
Go on up, brush your teeth and I'll tuck you in.
外婆能不能先給我講個故事
Can Grandma read me a story first?
求你啦 求你啦 求求你
Please, please please?
我想 我能應付過來
I think I can manage that.
走吧 外婆 我們走嘍
Come on, Grandma, let's go.
-謝謝你媽媽 -沒問題
- Thanks, Mom. - No problem.
哦我在廚灶裏給你留了晚飯
Oh, I left you some dinner by the stove.
謝謝
Thank you.
晚安 媽咪 我愛你
Good night, Mommy, I love you.
晚安 我也愛你
Good night, I love you.
我以為你三個月前就戒煙了
I thought you quit three months ago.
艾麗對你不做晚飯很是煩惱
Ally was bummed that you didn't make dinner.
我知道啊
I know she was.
你懂的 我只是趕不過來
You know, I just couldn't get here.
但是謝謝你今天從學校接她回來
But thank you for picking her up from school today.
那不算什麼
It's no problem.
-過來 -謝謝你
Come here. - Thank you.
-別熬太晚 孩子
Don't stay up too late, kiddo.
不會的
I won't.
晚安 媽媽
Good night, Mom.
晚安 甜心
Good night, sweetheart.
本·伍茲
Ben Woods.
嘿 本 我是泰勒博士
Hey Ben, it's Dr. Tyler.
泰勒博士 你好
Dr. Tyler.
我加入
I'm in.
我會去做的
I'll do it.
但我有幾個條件
I have a few conditions.
我們的會面必須是私下的
Our session needs to be private,
所以我不想待在一個標準的採訪室裏
so I don't wanna be in a standard interview room.
我們應該在他覺得舒服的某處會面
We should be somewhere where he feels comfortable,
在那裏他得至少能四處活動
where he can at least move around.
我是說 我們不會有任何進展
I mean we're not gonna get anywhere
如果我得不到他的信任
if I can't earn his trust.
-女士 -謝謝你
- Ma'am. - Thank you.
嘀嗒
Tick tock.
Tick, tock.
你那要幫忙嗎 博士
You need a hand with that, Doc?
我更喜歡被稱作泰勒博士或阿曼達
I prefer to be addressed as Dr. Tyler or Amanda.
請坐
Have a seat, please.
為便於記錄 請報上你的名字
State your name for the record.
傑克遜·邁克爾·謝伊
ackson Michael Shea.
78011號囚犯
Inmate 78011.
這一切都是有意義的 對嗎 博士
There's a point to all this, right Doc?
看著我人生計時沙漏中的沙子
Seeing as how the sand of my hourglass
就快要漏光
has just about run out.
我不覺得這對我有多大好處
I don't see this benefiting me very much.
我的計劃是找到
My plan is to get to the root cause
你過度暴力的根本原因
of your excessive violence.
你是說那些稱我為怪物的
You mean the newspaper and magazine stories
報紙雜誌吧
calling me a monster.
-我讀過你的檔案了 -然後呢
- I've read your file. - And what?
你已經讀了一些文章
You've read some papers.
其中一些認為那個監獄黑客
Some file a prison hack
在給我看了一些墨水斑點後
too stupid to make it on the outside
在監獄外寫我是非常愚蠢的
wrote about me after he showed me some inkblots.
你看了那該死的東西
You read that shit
然後就以為你已攻入了我的大腦
and think you're inside my head?
博士 你對我他媽的一無所知
Doc, you don't know a fucking thing about me.
你說得對 傑克
You're right, Jack.
我是特麼的對你一無所知
I don't know a fucking thing about you.
而且如果我瞭解你
And if I did,
就不會來這裏浪費我的時間或者你的
I wouldn't be here wasting my time, or yours.
你想讓我離開嗎
Would you like me to leave?
嘀 嗒
Tick, tock.
嘀 嗒 嘀 嗒
Tick, tock, tick, tick.
像你這樣漂亮的小妞在這裏做什麼
So what's a pretty little thing like you doing here?
你抽到那根倒霉的簽了
You draw the short straw?
是有關暴力的 傑克
It's about the violence, Jack.
如果我能準確還原時間 地點 起因
If I can pinpoint the time, the place, the cause,
那或許我至少能幫助停止這惡性循環
then maybe I can at least help stop the cycle.
現在我們有很重要的決定要做 不是嗎
Now we have some very important decisions to make, don't we?
-我們開始 -從我母親的母乳開始
Let's start-- - With my mother's tit milk.
我在嬰兒時期是否得到了足夠的母乳
Did I get enough as an infant
來合適地滋養我在這文明社會的人生呢
to properly nourish me for life in civilized society?
你得到了嗎
Did you?
嘀
Tick.
博士 你準備好聽一個故事了嗎
Doc, you ready to hear a story?
嘀 嗒
Tick, tock.
那是1985年的夏天
It was the summer of '85.
我們沒錢 所以我們不得不
We had no money, so we had to
搬進我舅舅邁克的房子
move into my Uncle Mike's single wide.
有時候 當我閉上眼睛
Sometimes, when I close my eyes,
我仍然能聞到那股拖車的霉味
I can still smell that musty trailer.
大熊想要裝作
Bigger bears try to pretend
它們來這附近看望朋友
that they came 'round the corner to look for a friend.
它們是來這附近看望朋友的
That they came 'round the corner to look for a frown.
等等
Hold on.
它們想裝作沒人在意的樣子
And they try to pretend that nobody cares.
不管你走在線上 還是走在方塊上
Whether you walk on the lines, or on the squares.
你的電話 辛西婭
Phone for you, Cynthia.
謝謝你 邁克
Thanks, Mike.
好了 現在 你邁克舅舅
Okay, well, your Uncle Mike's
會幫你讀完 好嗎
gonna help you finish reading, okay book?
晚安 媽咪
Good night, Mommy.
嘿 小伙
. Hey buddy.
嘿 邁克舅舅
Hey, hey Uncle Mike.
準備好聽你的 生日床頭故事了嗎
Ready for your birthday bedtime story?
人們總是談論上帝
People always talk about God.
那當我舅舅在半夜
Where was God when my Uncle
偷偷溜進我的臥室
was sneaking into my bedroom late at night,
給我講床前故事是 上帝去哪裏了
telling me bedroom stories,
我不想聽
I didn't wanna hear.
一切都會好起來的 孩子
Everything is gonna be okay, my son.
你現在是在上帝的面前
You are in the presence of the Lord now.
告訴我發生了什麼
Tell me what happened.
你母親是什麼反應
How did your mother react to the news?
並非你想的那樣
Not the way you'd think.
謝伊太太
Mrs. Shea, I'm,
真希望我是 因為別的原因而出現的
I really wish I were here under different circumstances,
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
這是關於你弟弟和你兒子的
It involves your brother and your son.
發生了什麼
Well what is it?
你兒子最近是不是行為很反常
Has, has your son been acting different lately?
他最近有沒有什麼奇怪的行為
Anything strange about his behavior?
我 我兒子是個好孩子
My, my. my son is a good boy.
是的
Yes he is.
知道該如何告訴你這件事 那我就直說吧
I don't know how to say this, so I'll just say it.
我們認為你的弟弟
We believe that your brother
涉嫌猥褻你兒子
has been inappropriately touching your son.
猥褻我兒子
Inappropriately touching my son?
你弟弟一直在猥褻你的孩子 謝伊太太
Your brother's been molesting your son, Mrs. Shea.
這不可能
That is not true.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
我不信
That is not true.
我不知道你從哪聽說的
I don't know where you got that, but,
但這不是事實
that ain't true.
謝伊太太 是你兒子告訴我的
Mrs. Shea, your son told me.
對不起
I'm sorry.
這說不通
That don't make no sense.
這並不是真的
這是 這是個謊言
That's a, that's a lie.
這絕對不是真的
That is a goddamn lie.
你在造謠
You're making up stories.
然後你帶著你的慌話 和你的假故事來到
And you come in here with your lies and your stories.
現在你可以離開了
You need to go.
趕快離開我的房子
You need to get the hell outta here.
趕緊走
You need to get the hell outta my house.
滾出我的房子
I said get the hell outta my house.
走 趕緊離開這
Get out, get outta here.
這都是你編造的
And your lies, and your stories.
我不知道你在說些什麼
I don't know what you're talking about.
你到底對我的孩子做了什麼
What the hell did you do to my boy?
我是受害者
I was the victim.
但我也可能是犯罪者
But I may as well have been the perpetrator
以她的反應來看
from the way she reacted.
我說了滾出去
I said to get outta my house.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
願上帝與你同在
May God be with you.
這是我家
This is my house!
是我家
It's my house!
什麼你要到這裏 對我說這樣的事
Come in here, saying things like that to me.
不久以後辛西婭·謝伊
Cynthia Shea drank herself to death
醺酒致死
pretty soon after.
也許是他殺
Killed, maybe.
你覺得呢
What do you think?
我從小注定是個罪犯 還是
Destined from a tender age to be a criminal, or.
目前來看
Well it's too soon in the process
下結論還為時過早
for me to form an opinion on that.
你的項目到底是什麼
What exactly is your process?
我知道你對病理標誌制度很瞭解
I know that you're familiar with the flag system.
所以我在尋找顯現出的信號
So I am looking for signs that stand out.
並盡早識別出危險標誌
And recognizing the red flags early enough
這樣就可以把暴力扼殺在搖籃裏
so that the violence can be stopped.
所以 現在讓我們談談你的舅舅
So, let's talk about your uncle.
在17歲以前我一直和他住在一起
I lived with him until about the time I was 17.
當我長大以後 他就把注意力轉移到
After I got too old, Uncle Mike turned his attentions
他女朋友的孩子身上去了
to the kid of the girl he'd been seeing.
那個女人並未察覺
She didn't suspect a damn thing.
看到他在那個小男孩身後追逐玩耍
Seeing him chase after that little boy,
我的思維突然中斷
something just snapped.
不 不要過來 求你了
No no, please, God.
我得到了啟發和自由
I felt illuminated and free.
自由
Free?
是的 這是我人生中第一次
Well it was the first time in my life
掌握了那些一直引導我的東西
I was ever in control of the events that guided me.
沒有比這更自由的了
Nothing's more freeing than that.
你明明就可以阻止他
You know you could've stopped him
而非把他打成重傷住進醫院
without putting him in the hospital.
但你選擇了憤怒
You chose to fly into a rage.
你還沒明白嗎 醫生
Don't you get it, Doc?
我們都是被關在籠子裏的動物
We're all just caged animals.
有著動物一樣的天性
With animal instincts.
時間到了 泰勒醫生
Time's up, Dr. Tyler.
來自韋科市和其他城市的消防員稱
Firefighters from Waco and other cities
由於乾燥天氣和風況
report that due to dry weather and wind conditions,
火災仍是一個巨大的威脅
the fire is still very much an active threat
對於當地群眾來說
to local communities,
要時刻準備好緊急疏散
and that evacuation orders will remain in place.
現今15%的火災已得到有效遏制
The fire is currently reported to be 15% contained.
敬請期待 更多消息
More information on this ongoing story
將會後續報道
will be reported as it becomes available.
親愛的 我很想你
God, I miss you.
嚴肅法紀
Looking at law and order,
對德克薩斯州的犯人傑克遜·謝伊的處決
the impending execution of Texas inmate Jackson Shea
明確地表明了在德克薩斯州
shines a harsh light on capital punishment
法律與秩序在政府處罰的作用
in the Lone Star State.
由於公眾輿論的兩面性
Due to vocal public opinion on both sides of the issue,
州長宣佈對於是否處決謝伊先生
the Governor has announced a final review of the possibility
即將進行最後的審判
for a stay of execution in Mr. Shea's case
基於阿曼達·泰勒醫生的權威
under the authority of Dr. Amanda Tyler,
一位著名的犯罪心理學家
a noted criminal psychologist.
州長公佈了泰勒醫生的發現
The Governor has stated that Dr. Tyler's findings
這些發現將會成為
will likely be a key factor
決定德州法制部門如何判決
in determining what action
的關鍵因素
the Texas Department of Criminal Justice will take.
準備好了嗎 傑克
You ready to start, Jack?
法官讓我自己選擇
The judge gave me a choice.
是去軍事學校還是少教所
Either go to military school, or go to juvie.
我輕鬆完成了基礎訓練
I breeze through basic training,
被狙擊手學校選中 因為我視力良好
get selected for sniper school because I have 20/10 vision,
並且出色完成射擊
and I aced marksmanship.
但是你的檔案上說你其實
Well your file says that you actually
被軍事學校開除了
got kicked out of military school.
給了你18個月的假釋
That resulted in parole left 18 months.
我們的行為都是有後果的 傑克
There's consequences for our actions, Jack.
行動
Action.
後果
Reaction.
行動 你把你的舅舅打進了醫院
Action, you put your uncle in the hospital.
後果 你被監禁18個月
Reaction, you get sentenced to 18 months.
18個月 服役12個月
18 months, served 12.
所以這代表著什麼
So this is, what?
制度的失敗
An example of the system failing?
你認為你凌駕於法律之上
You think you're above the law?
你欺騙過保險公司嗎 醫生
You ever cheat the insurance companies, Doc?
給一位病人開了現金賬單
Bill a patient for cash and put in a claim for it.
同時也開出醫療保險賬單
Us in the know call t
我們都知道這叫雙倍計費
hat double back billing.
第一道防線
First line of defense
抵抗千年蟲
against the Y2K buzz,
檢查了每個計算機確保
checking each machine to make sure
它在2000年能正常工作
it works properly in the year 2000.
米婭 能給我來點猛的嗎
Mia, could you give us two fingers of the good stuff?
好的 馬蒂
Yes, Marty.
我在監獄裏認識了馬蒂
I met Marty in prison.
他在圈內很有名
Let's just say he was someone in the know.
我出獄後 他給了我一份工作
Once I got out, he offered me a job,
面對現實吧 誰還會雇一個囚犯呢
'cause let's face it, who else is gonna hire a con?
聽我說 孩子
Listen to me, kid.
我說的是 醫生 律師 牙醫
I'm talking about doctors, lawyers, dentists.
他們擁有大量現金用來逃稅
Large amounts of cash that don't get reported to the IRS.
所以當這些錢丟了的時候
Won't be reported to the cops
他們也不會報警
if it comes up missing.
他們把錢藏在辦公室的衣櫃裏
They hide their money in a coat closet in their office,
或是床底的鞋盒裏
or in a shoe box under the bed.
曾有一位律師
There was this one lawyer,
他竟然在咖啡罐裏藏了兩萬五千美元
he hid 25,000 fucking dollars in a coffee can
然後他把咖啡罐藏在了微波爐裏
that he stuck in a microwave.
這才是關鍵 對吧
There's a point somewhere here, right?
對的 是關鍵
Yeah, this is the point.
我的那個白癡保釋官
That dickhead parole officer I have?
他給我一份清理辦公室的夜間工作
He got me a night job cleaning office buildings.
你好
HEY
這個夥計 他是新來的
This guy, he's gotta replace
二樓清潔工
the ShopVac on the second floor.
我關心這個嗎
The hell I care for?
簽個名就可以了
Just sign the damn board.
這裏面有個婦科專家
Now in one of these buildings is a gynecologist,
他會給那些付現金的女人打折
who gives a discount to women who pay cash,
然後他給她們的保險公司開賬單
and then he bills their insurance company.
找到了
There it is.
他的保險箱在櫃子裏
He's got a safe in his closet
而且保險箱還有縫隙
that is bursting out the fucking seams.
我們會得到多少錢
How much money are we talking about?
誰也不知道 除非我們打開了它
We won't know 'til we open it.
這個醫生肯定是個白癡
This doctor must be some kinda idiot.
他買的鑲嵌式保險櫃
He buys himself a wall safe,
卻把它放衣櫃裏了
but he doesn't put it in a wall.
錘子呢
You got the hammer, kid?
快拿出錘子來 快點
What're you doing, get the chisel, come on, man, come on.
快
Come on.
就沿著它的邊 很好砸的 快
Now just go down the sides, it's soft there, come on.
太好了
Yes.
我們打開前不知道多少錢 但我告訴你
We won't know until we open it, but I can tell you this.
如果有人覺得很必要
If someone finds it necessary
在他們的辦公室裏藏一個無線保險箱
to hide an unwired safe in their office,
一般來說 他都有一個很恰當的理由
generally speaking, it's for a very good reason.
天啊
Damn.
就像在擠奶
Just like milking a tit, kid.
快 把這些裝好後就溜
Come on, pack it up, get the fuck outta here
早飯時在我那接頭
and meet me back at my place for breakfast.
你聽我的
You listen to me.
按我說的做 然後我們兩個
You do what I say, and both of us
都可以偷溜掉
could make our Mike bend it.
等一下
. Hey
你忘了簽名
You forgot to sign out.
抱歉
Sorry.
我小時候非常窮 但是現在
I grew up poor, but there I was,
我眼前的的錢 比我母親一年的工資都高
staring at more money than my Mama made in a year.
一萬六千四百美元
' 65400
拿吧 你拿一半
Go ahead, take your half.
一半
Half?
當然了 我們可是合作夥伴
Yeah, we're partners.
分你一半
Take half,
合作夥伴就是這樣分的 一人一半
that's what partners do, right down the middle.
快 拿著它
Come on, take it, take it, take it.
只要你遵循規則 我們就會成為富豪
So long as you follow the rules, we're golden.
第一天規則
Number one rule.
你要保持一副完全無害的樣子
You gotta stay innocuous.
不要讓他們注意到你
Don't let them see you coming.
你知道 警察在調查搶劫案時
You know the cops in robbery,
他們通常都會找那些
they're looking for the asshole
走在大街上
who's walking down the street
在搶劫案發生後
with a shiny new
還帶著嶄新的勞力士手錶的蠢貨
Rolex the day after a big heist.
一旦你被他們盯上 那你就完了
And once you're pegged, you're pegged.
我的意思是 夥計 你可以給自己
I mean, kid you could buy yourself
時不時的買雙新鞋
a new pair of shoes once in a while,
但你穿著手工西裝去百老匯街上晃悠
but you go walking down Broadway in a silk Italian suit?
那你佘生就只能在號子裏度過了
You'll be in a lineup for the rest of your life.
我們是一條繩上的螞蚱 對嗎
We on the same train here, kid?
是的
Yeah.
而且這輛車早已離站
I'd say that train left the station.
你不應該再喝咖啡了
You gotta stop drinking coffee.
打開它
Open that up.
它會造成胃穿孔
It's gonna put a hole in your stomach.
咖啡對你最有害了
It's the worst thing for you, coffee.
對你的神經也不好
It's bad for your nerves.
喝酒比喝咖啡好一點兒
This'll make it a little better,
但還是不喝的好
but you really should stop that.
我們是朋友 你懂我的意思麼
I'm your friend, you know what I mean?
你的前路一片光明
You got a big future.
為一起犯罪而乾杯
Here's to crime.
誰說犯罪一無所成
Who says crime doesn't pay?
為健康乾杯
Salud.
我是馬丁的徒弟 馬丁是我的導師
I was a student, Marty the teacher.
我們一起犯了三次案之後
After our third job together,
馬蒂開始檢驗我的犯罪技巧
Marty put me to the test.
找到我自己獨特的犯罪方式
Find a mark of my own.
所以我去看了些當地的牙醫
So I checked out a few local dentists.
醫生 我沒有醫保卡
Hey Doc, I don't have an insurance card,
付現金可以打折麼
do you give discounts for cash?
恐怕不行
'Fraid not.
只能是醫保卡
Insurance and cards only.
嘴張大點兒 你好像長了顆蛀牙
Open wide, seems like you've got a bad cavity.
到了第三個牙醫的時候
By the third dentist,
我的牙齦腫脹的好像
my gums were so swollen that my teeth felt like
我的牙都要掉下來似的
they were ready to fall out.
但是 我的牙確實是乾淨的很了
But, I had the cleanest mouth in the city.
我都沒想到你這麼笨
I can't believe you'd be so stupid.
你一天洗了幾次牙
How many times can you get your teeth cleaned in one day?
我們一起找個辦法
Here we are.
牙醫
Dentists.
下午好
Good afternoon,
感謝致電陽光牙科醫院
thank you for calling Sunshine Dental.
你好 請問你們提供
Hello, do you offer
老人折扣和現金優惠嗎
senior and cash discounts?
哦 先生 我們提供
Oh, yes sir, we do.
哦 你們提供啊
Oh, you do.
你們提供現金優惠啊
You do offer discounts for cash.
對的 我們提供
Too right, we do.
很好
Well that's fantastic.
非常感謝
Thank you very much.
您願意先預約
Well would you care to make an
孩子 你今兒吸取了什麼教訓
What's the moral of your story, kid?
你用手指一行行劃過這些黃頁
Let your fingers do the walking through the Yellow Pages.
這是什麼
What's this?
聖誕禮物
That is a Christmas present.
所以這就是那種
So it's one of those,
天上掉餡餅的事
too good to be true type of deals.
打開保險櫃之前
We don't know what's in the fucking safe
我們都不知道裏面有什麼
until we open it, right?
起來吧
Come on.
我不能坐在這兒
I can't sit here.
我討厭這個沙發
I hate that couch,
有一回我看見裏面有隻老鼠
you know I found a rat in there once.
我坐之前你怎麼不說
Why didn't you tell me that before I sat on it?
至少在你睡在上面之前
Before you slept on it.
利奧·弗蘭克 一個律師
Leo Frank, attorney at law.
馬丁的一個老朋友提供的消息
The tip game from an old friend of Martin's
這個朋友還在服刑 出來以後需要一筆錢
who was still doing time and needed a stake when he got out.
馬丁答應給他兩成
Martin agreed to put away 20% for him.
時機正好
Right on time.
好了 我們從樓那邊的
Alright, we gain access through the maintenance door
維修門過去
on the side of the building.
開始行動
Let's go.
-保險櫃在哪兒 -在那兒吧檯後面
- Where's the safe? - There it is, behind the bar.
正如他所說
Just like he said.
既然你不想竊聽
Now why would you go through all the trouble
為什麼在這個保險櫃上這麼折騰
with a safe like that if you're not gonna wire it?
你沒法竊聽不存在的東西
You don't hardwire something that doesn't exist.
老前輩你確定這麼干沒問題麼
You sure about this, old man?
-該死 -怎麼了
- Shit. - What?
-電池沒電了 -你在逗我麼
- Battery's dead. - Are you kidding me?
你帶備用電池了沒
Do you have any extras?
手電筒裏倒是有一個 能行麼
There's one in the flashlights, will those work?
不行 這個要用3A型號的
No, this takes AAA.
我好像找到了點兒什麼
Think I found something.
快把那個拿開 真噁心
Get out of here with that, it's disgusting.
拿好了
Hold on.
你不知道這個以前在哪兒
You don't know where that's been.
你不要臉皮了麼
Have you no decency?
去門口望望風
Just watch the door.
電池裝好了馬蒂
Wrap it up, Marty.
好了
Okay, okay, alright.
好
Yes.
你知道證據開示
Did you know that motion for discovery
是指原告和被告
means the prosecutor and the defendant
必須交換與案件相關的
must exchange all evidence and information
所有證據和信息麼
pertinent to a case?
66萬美元先減去兩成再對半分
$660,000, divided by two, minus 20%,
今晚收穫頗豐 小伙子
is a great night's work, man.
該死
Fuck.
怎麼了
What?
我也不知道 馬蒂 只是
I don't know, Marty, it's just.
我知道當天上掉餡餅的時候
I know when something is too good to be true.
你什麼意思
What's your point?
我的意思是沒有那麼多裝滿了
My point is that there's not that many safes lying around
無用的現金的保險櫃
with this kinda cash in it
等著你去偷
that aren't for something special.
你怎麼了
What's the matter with you?
你瘋了麼 拜託
Are you mental? Come on.
我是認真的
I'm serious.
馬蒂如果你想要的話
Marty, I will take the money back for you,
我會把和今晚相同的錢帶回來給你
tonight, if you want.
孩子 你在說些什麼
Kid, what're you talking about?
我們不能把錢放回去
We can't put it back.
我們拿上錢 在沙灘上買個公寓
We take the money, and buy a condo on the beach somewhere,
和遲暮的太太們一起玩推圓盤遊戲
play shuffleboard with the old ladies.
只是 我們要離開這個小鎮
Just, get outta town.
好 我答應你
Okay, okay, I'll make you a deal.
給我一周時間讓我收收尾
Give me one week to tie up some loose ends.
然後我去德克薩斯找這個朋友
And then I've got this friend in Texas,
我本想介紹你們認識
I was gonna introduce you to him.
但是我們會拿上錢 會離開這兒
But we'll take the money, we'll leave town.
只要一周
One week.
這是我唯一的要求
It's all I ask.
行麼
Okay?
羅伯特
Robert?
-貝爾蒙特先生 -對
Mr. Belmont? - Yeah.
這是威廉懷爾德隊長搶劫部門的
This is Captain William Wilder, robbery division.
事實是這樣的 米基
The point is this, Micky?
我都雇了很多警察了 不需要再來一個
I got plenty of cops on payroll, I don't need another one.
隊長給你帶來了一個商業機密
The captain's got a business proposal for you.
聽著 貝爾蒙特先生
Look, Mr. Belmont.
我妻子需要一個全新的廚房
My wife wants an entirely new kitchen.
我兒子需要在地下室裏打造一個娛樂室
My sons want an entertainment room in the basement.
我需要一個獨立的浴室
And I want my own bathroom
這樣我就不用看
so I don't have to look
我妻子的那些該死的壁掛了
at my wife's shit hanging on the shower.
我看起來像一個室內裝修設計師麼
Do I look like an interior decorator to you?
並不
No.
那我為什麼要聽你說你妻子
Then why do I give a fuck about your wife's shit
在浴室裏放的該死的壁掛
handing in the bathroom?
情報
Information.
鮑勃聽他說完
Bob, hear him out.
你得為我想要的東西買單 貝爾蒙特先生
You gonna pay for these things I want, Mr. Belmont.
作為是誰偷了你保險櫃的情報來交換
Plus a little bonus in exchange
還得給我一筆錢
for the man who robbed your safe.
你還是小心點兒的好 警隊先生
You oughtta be very careful, Mr. Police Captain,
否則某天你就會消失在你的警區
or you might find yourself missing in your own precinct.
-羅伯特 -嗯
- Robert. - Yeah.
那個人是個手段老道的慣偷
The man is an old school thief.
膽子很大
The kind that has steel for balls.
常常入室行竊
Second story guy.
你的保險櫃被偷以後利奧就來找我了
Leo comes to me after your safe was robbed
我私下裏打聽了一下
and I do a little quiet poking around.
線人告訴我
My contacts tell me that he's living
他住在一個百貨公司的地下室裏
in a basement of a department store.
你想知道地址麼
You wanna know the address?
你妻子喜歡什麼樣的廚房
What kinda kitchen does your wife like?
難纏的傢伙 你把我的錢弄哪兒去了
Where's my money, tough guy?
我不知道
I don't know.
我發誓我真的不知道
I swear I don't know.
天啊
Jesus.
搜查這地方
Search the place.
你是個頑固的狗娘養
You're a stubborn son of a bitch.
這是把你推進地獄的催化劑
The catalyst that launched you into hell.
用地獄來形容未免太過了
Hell might be a bit extreme.
那你覺得應該是什麼
Well what would you call it?
-煉獄 -預言
Purgatory? - Anticipation.
你知道 那種在陷入
You know, that intense feeling you get
明知會改變你人生軌跡的東西之前的
right before you jump into something
強烈的感覺
that you know will change your life forever.
我覺得煉獄這個詞也不錯
I guess purgatory's as good a word as anyway.
雙手放在方向盤上
Put your hands on the steering wheel.
把自己銬在方向盤上
Handcuff yourself to the steering wheel.
向前拉
Pull forward.
你得告訴我是誰殺了馬丁·比格
You're gonna tell me who murdered Martin Bigg.
告訴我那個人的名字
I need a name.
我不能說
I can't.
-告訴我名字 -我不能說他會殺了我
- I need a name. - I can't, he'll kill me.
那你就不怕我嗎
What about me?
你要是不告訴我他的名字
I will kill you right here, right now,
我馬上就地殺了你
unless you give me a fucking name.
羅伯特·貝爾蒙特
Robert Belmont.
放開我
Let go.
他是關鍵人物
He's the key.
羅伯特 貝爾蒙特
Robert Belmont.
頭號放高利貸者和商人
Big time loan shark and business man.
他不難追蹤
He wasn't hard to track down.
我開始兼職司機
I started moonlighting as a chauffeur,
載著這個狗娘養的
driving the son of a bitch.
瞭解他的行程
Learned his routine.
我甚至從他情婦的家裏接過他
I even picked him up from his mistress's place.
我等他喝酒的時候
I always had a drink waiting for him.
有一天晚上 我在酒裏偷偷加了點料
And then one night, I slipped in a little something extra.
你醒了
There he is.
早上好 陽光明媚
Morning, sunshine.
我還擔心我加料加多了呢
I was worried I put a little too much in your drink.
放開我 你個慫包
Untie me, you piss ant fuck.
再怎麼粗魯都沒用
There's no need to be rude.
好吧
Okay, alright.
你說得沒錯
You proved your point.
放開我 告訴我你想要什麼
Now untie me and tell me what you want.
哇哦
Wow.
孩子 你膽量不錯
You got balls, kid.
你想要的我可以給你
I'll give that to you.
你知道 你可能就是
You know, you may just be
我一直在找的那種人
the guy that I've been looking for.
那種能把我的業務提升的人
The guy that's gonna take my business to the next level.
真是個冷笑話
I fail to see what's so funny.
你被孤零零的綁在椅子上
You're alone, tied to a chair.
以你現在的狀況
What about this situation leads you to believe
你怎麼會覺得還能和我討價還價
you're in a position suitable for bargaining?
好
. Okay
放了我 你走吧
Untie me, and walk away.
我們就當這事沒發生過
We'll just let this one go.
你還是沒搞清楚狀況 博比
You're not paying attention, Bobby.
你之所以還活著
The only reason you're still alive,
是因為我還沒殺你
is I haven't killed you yet.
你想要多少錢
How much?
我會給你喝杯這個
I will give you this.
你對威士忌的品味還不賴
You have fine taste in whiskey.
你到底要多少錢
How much?
別動 博比
Stay with me, Bobby, boy.
別動
Stay with me.
一百萬
One million.
你還記得這個吧 對吧
You remember this, don't you?
自大狂
You arrogant fuck.
這是我搭檔的
This belonged to my partner.
他不知道那是你的錢
He didn't know the money was yours.
你本可以放過他一次的
You could've, let that one go.
你兄弟就是個混蛋
Your partner was a degenerate fuck, alright?
他從我這偷錢
He stole from me.
我該怎麼做 像個兄弟似地拍拍他嗎
What am I supposed to do, just pat him on the back?
去他媽的
Fuck that.
噢 好吧 對不起
Okay, alright, I'm sorry.
200萬
Two million.
你話太多了 鮑勃
You talk too much, Bob.
我對你的錢沒興趣
I'm not interested in your money.
你折磨我的兄弟
You tortured my friend.
你折磨他
You tortured him,
你讓他像被宰的豬一樣流血到死
and let him bleed to death like a pig.
這是替馬蒂做的
This is for Marty.
我只是讓那個雜種知道
I gave that bastard a preview
在地獄等著他的是什麼
of what's waiting for him in hell.
貝爾蒙特只是遭到了報應
Belmont got what he deserved,
但是醫生 我想讓你知道
but I wanna make one thing real clear to you, Doc.
那並不是謀殺
I didn't commit murder.
我是在伸張正義
I performed an execution.
-這是有區別的 -胡說八道
There's a difference. Bullshit.
根本沒區別你也知道的
I don't believe that, and neither do you.
你說得挺多 但是你想表明的是什麼呢
You talk a lot, but what can you really speak for?
可以為我辯護嗎
Can you speak for me?
-我想問你個問題 -別廢話了
- I wanna ask you a question. - Tick, tock.
當我被處決的時候 你會在乎我嗎
When it's my time, will you care about me then?
當第一根針慢慢
That moment when the needle, the very first one,
刺入我的身體 我漸漸失去意識的時候
slips into my body and relaxes my nerves.
你會看著我嗎
Are you gonna watch me?
會嗎 抑或轉頭看向別處呢
Are you gonna watch me, or are you gonna turn and look away?
第二根針令我無法呼吸的時候
When the second needle freezes my lungs,
你會驚恐地去扒那些
are you gonna scribble scrabble
寫滿計劃的便條薄嗎
in your notepad for future reference?
到第三根針時 我的心臟停止跳動
And when that third needle stops my heart,
隨之他們宣佈我死亡
and they pronounce my body dead,
你是為我的死亡感到悲痛呢
are you gonna anguish over my death?
還是會法律伸張了正義
Or are you gonna rejoice
而感到欣慰呢
that the law of your land was fulfilled?
都不會
Neither.
你見過死亡的過程嗎 醫生
You ever see anyone die, Doc?
你見到過人們眼中的光
You ever watch as the light fades
漸漸黯淡最後熄滅
out of someone's eyes as they just,
飄散得無影無蹤嗎
drift away into nothing?
那不關你的事
It's none of your fucking business.
這不是我的事
It's not about me.
就是你的事
This is about you.
所有的一切都是你的遊戲
This whole game has been about you.
你那狗屁的狂妄態度對我不起用 醫生
Your bullshit cocky attitude isn't gonna work with me, Doc.
跟我沒關係
It's not about me.
我不
I don't,
他媽不在乎跟你有沒有關係
I don't fucking care if it's about you.
去你的那些狗屁問題
Fuck your questions, fuck you.
我不玩了
I'm done.
我不會再陪你玩這狗屁遊戲
I'm not playing your fucking games anymore.
我說結束的時候才是結束
You're done playing games when I tell you.
懂嗎
Got it?
所有證據應該都已經在火災中毀了
Any evidence should have been destroyed in the fire,
所以我覺得是時候離開這了
so I figured it was time to leave the city.
你知道這是誰的地盤嗎
You know who runs this place?
查理羅斯先生
Mr. Charlie Rose.
不用找了
Keep the change.
我在馬蒂的德克薩斯州的旅行書上
I found an address in Marty's
發現了一個地址
Texas travel book.
然後她出現了
And then there she was.
她是我見過最美的女人
She was the most beautiful woman I'd ever laid my eyes on.
-晚上好啊 -嗨 貝利
- Good evening. - Hello, Billy.
我們有位貴賓吧
I believe we have a guest.
就在那
Right over there.
你真是個寶寶
Aren't you a sweetie.
打擾一下 我們見過嗎
I'm sorry, have we met?
沒有
Not exactly.
奧利維亞
Olivia.
-傑克遜 -謝依我知道的
- Jackson. - Shea, yes.
馬丁比格是我們共同的朋友
Martin Bigg was a mutual friend.
放心我不是警察
Oh don't worry, I'm not a cop.
不過你對貝爾蒙特做出的事 可夠勁兒的
But that was quite a job you did on Belmont.
你怎麼知道就是我幹的
Who says that was me?
我自有方法
I have my sources.
我不喜歡被別人跟著
I don't like being followed.
看出來了
Noted.
和我跳舞吧
Dance with me.
你當不了警察一定是因為你大美了
And you're too pretty to be a cop.
我不認識馬丁
I didn't know Martin.
但我的父親跟他很熟
But my father, very close to him.
你父親是誰
Who's your father?
查理·羅斯
Charlie Rose.
和你一樣
Just like you.
他也是個商人
He's a business man.
哪種商人
What kinda business?
收購業
Acquisitions.
你怎麼知道在哪可以找到我的
How'd you know where to find me?
看看這周圍
You seen this place?
只要有新人 我就會知道
Somebody new walks into town, I hear about it.
另外 小貝利可是我的人
Besides, little Billy over there has a sweet spot for me.
想那啥不
Wanna take a ride?
帶路
Lead the way.
-嗨 姑娘們 -早上好
- Hi ladies. - Good morning.
-嘿 爸爸 -我女兒醒了
- Hey Daddy. - Well, my daughter's awake.
爸爸 這是傑克·謝依
Daddy, meet Jack Shea.
傑克 這是查理
Jack, meet Charlie.
羅斯先生
Mr. Rose.
馬蒂從來沒說過你是這樣的老手
Marty never said you were such a city slicker.
有問題嗎
Is that gonna be a problem?
不 沒問題 除非你不安分
No, not a problem, unless you make it that way.
你們現在還沒在一起 對吧
You all didn't do nothing together, now, did you?
噢 爸爸
Oh, Daddy.
好了 我只是和你開玩笑
Oh, come on, I'm just playing with you.
過來聊一會
Come on over here and chat for a while.
姑娘們 你們為什麼不進屋涼快去呢
Ladies, why don't you go on inside and cool off a bit?
哦 寶貝
Aw, baby.
-哈爾 -是的 老闆
- Hal? - Yes sir.
姑娘們 請離開游泳池 馬上
Ladies, outta the pool, now.
你知道我很喜歡年輕的活力
You know I like to harness the energy of youth.
來瓶啤酒嗎
You want a beer?
聽著 羅斯先生 我來這的原因是
Look, Mr. Rose, the only reason I'm here
馬蒂說他在德克薩斯州有個朋友
is because Marty said he had a friend in Texas,
就是這樣
and that's it.
馬蒂就是個爛好人
Marty, Marty was thick as a brick.
但他對人的判斷很準
But he was a tremendous judge of character.
表面來看 你是達標的
Now, from appearance, you look like you're up to the mark,
但我關心的是內在
but it's what's underneath that concerns me.
如果你只是有勇無謀
If you'll crack when the heat gets cranked up.
你也不會有什麼出息
You gotta keep a low profile.
我這一生
I've been my entire life,
什麼都嘗試過
and I never got so much as a hockey ticket.
除了賭馬和石油
I only do outside horses and oil,
我不在住的地方拉屎 你要明白我的意圖
and I don't shit where I live, if you catch my drift.
我花了一整年的時間 只做一件事
I spend a whole year, an entire year, on a single project.
但是報酬一直可觀
But the payoff is always worthwhile.
價值少於500萬
And I don't touching nothing,
我不會動手
unless it'll fetch at least five million U.S.
我有一個團隊 大家輪流做隊長
I use a crew, and I rotate who's in charge.
當奧利維亞不製造混亂時
Olivia there sometimes acts as another guy,
她也會一樣的出任務
when she's not causing chaos.
要知道 我從不用來自德克薩斯以外的人
You know, I never hire a man unless they're a Texas man.
我只是不信任他們
I just don't trust 'em.
但是馬緹和我親如兄弟
But Marty was a brother to me.
所以我不會把你丟出去
So I'm not gonna throw you out.
但你必須證明你自己
But you're gonna have to prove yourself.
你認為怎麼樣
What do you think there, blue eyes?
我們什麼時候開始
When do we get started?
7千5百萬怎麼樣
How does 75 mil sound?
下午好 斯特伯諾維特茲先生 和太太
Good afternoon, Mr. and Ms. Stroblekowitz.
-今天怎麼樣 -很好 謝謝
How're y'all doing today? - Very well, thank you.
比克爾先生已經在等你們了
Mr. Beeker's ready for you.
弗林會帶你們去樓上
Flynn'll be taking you upstairs.
請跟我來
Please follow me.
-謝謝你 -祝心情愉快
- Thank you. - Y'all have a great day.
-謝謝 -謝謝
- Thank you. - Thank you.
西蒙·貝克爾 你所聽說過的
Simon Beeker was the president of the largest bank
最大銀行的總裁
nobody ever heard of.
貝克爾掌握著跨洋的金融業務
Beeker handled overseas financial transactions,
以及資金的流向
how the money flowed.
貝克爾沒有獲得一點利益
Just none of it flowed to Beeker.
貝克爾先生 你的客人到了
Mr. Beeker, your clients have arrived.
嗨
Hi.
下午好
Afternoon.
-請坐 -謝謝
- Please, have a seat. - Thank you.
有什麼可以幫你的
What can I do for you?
我們代表羅斯先生
We represent Mr. Rose's interests.
是的 貝克爾先生
Yes, Mr. Beeker.
櫻桃 你能讓保羅進來嗎
Cherry, can you send Paul in, please?
馬上
Right away.
嗯
Um.
我
I, uh,
我沒想到你這麼快
I didn't expect you so soon.
時間加快了
The timeline's moved up.
好了 貝克爾先生
Now, Mr. Beeker.
地下室的密碼每天都換
We know the Vault's codes change daily.
你的人在晚上十一點出現
Now your man, they show up at 11:00 PM,
非常準時
not a second sooner or later,
輸入密碼 我們就能過上好日子
with the codes, and we're golden.
之後 我們就可以頤養天年了
Anything after that, we're not gonna do business.
貝克爾先生
Now, Mr. Beeker.
地下室裏有價值7干5百萬的債券
We know that there's 75 million in bonds in that vault.
7干5百萬 聽起來太棒了
75 mil sounds good.
這次 我要做領隊
But this time I'm the leading man.
-噢 不女士 你不行 -先生 我行的
- No ma'am, you are not. - Oh yes sir, I am.
希望你能原諒 但是你不行
I beg your pardon, missy, but you are not.
爸爸
Daddy.
好吧
. Okay
各退一步吧 小姑娘
You wanna wheel and deal, missy?
你帶上哈爾
You take Hal.
我懂 老闆
Got you, boss.
我會好好照顧她的
I'll take real good care of her.
不 我不會帶哈爾
No, I am not taking Hal.
你真不帶
Do we have a deal?
羅斯先生的分利是10%
Mr. Rose's cut is 10 cents on the dollar.
聽明白了嗎
Do I make myself clear?
是的 明白了
Yeah, that's understood.
好吧 合作愉快
Alright then, pleasure doing business with you.
好吧 成交 不帶哈爾
Okay, deal, no Hal.
-乾杯 -乾杯
- Cheers. - Cheers.
很開心
I was happy.
就像是 第一次
It seemed like, just for once,
我得到了上帝的眷顧
God smiled down on me.
你知道我多愛你嗎
You know how much I love you?
我很愛你
I love you so much.
我對你至死不渝
I love you forever.
是的
Yeah.
我有個活 需要一個司機
I got a job, I need a driver.
讓我來
Yeah, I can drive.
我能得多少
How much?
正常水平
The usual amount.
什麼時候開始
What time do y'all need me there?
這幾天吧
Couple days.
保持手機通暢
Keep your phone on.
隨時聽候
I'll be in touch.
好了
It's done.
有時你得把韁繩抓在手裏
Sometimes you gotta keep the training wheels on,
即使它們想自由
even though they wanna roll alone.
我們包圍了這裏
We cased the place.
我們有設計圖 守衛時間表
We had blueprints, guard schedules,
查理甚至弄來了安全系統的備份
and Charlie even had a duplicate
來給我練習
of the security system made for me to practice.
一切準備就緒
We had all the bases covered.
好的
Okay.
我們穿的像去參加葬禮一樣
We look like we're dressed for a funeral.
我看見你把兄弟們帶來了
I see you brought your boyfriends,
密碼帶了嗎
did you bring the codes?
這就是我們來這的原因 傑克
That's why we're here, Jack.
那麼開始幹活吧
Then let's get to work.
-嘿 -直盯著掃瞄器好嗎
Hey, keep an eye on the scanners, alright?
確保無死角監控
Make sure all the edges are sealed.
這是貝克爾的私人樓層
This is Beeker's private floor.
沒有攝像頭
There's no cameras here.
走這邊
There you go.
貝克爾用攝像頭
Beeker put the security cameras
把金庫全方位的監控起來了
in the vault on loop.
幹得好
Nice.
我們爭取了一小時
We got an hour,
然後貝克爾來分他的那一份
then Beeker will be here to get his cut.
密碼
Codes.
給
Here.
如果其中一個數字是錯的
If even one of those numbers is wrong,
我們就要被警察甕中捉鱉了
half the police department'll show up outside.
聽著 小姐
Listen, little lady.
這是貝克爾親口告訴我的
I got it from Beeker himself.
我一字不差的寫下來的
Wrote the numbers down exactly the way he told me.
壓力會讓人出錯的
Pressure changes things.
讓一個人寫6而不是9
Makes a man write a six instead of a nine.
不是貝克爾 他很堅強
Not Beeker, the man's ice.
我說的是你
I was talking about you.
你倆吵完了嗎
You two about done bickering?
你老公是個弱雞
Your husband's a prick.
你能夠得更好的
You could do so much better.
呦 這是啥
Yo, what's it doing?
校準報警器
It's synchronized the alarms,
正在破譯階段
it's deciphering codes in stages.
每個階段的顏色不同
Each stage has a different color.
我們在等什麼啊
What the hell are we waiting for?
等這個
That.
貝克爾在車裏
Beeker's in the van.
我們會在那分錢
We'll split the bonds up there.
你知道的 有件事一直困擾我
You know, something's been bothering me.
貝克爾為什麼要來
Now why would Beeker show up here in person
讓自己陷入危險
and put himself at risk?
該死
Fuck.
奧利維亞 趴下
Olivia, stay down.
奧利維亞 我們必須立刻離開
Olivia, we gotta get the fuck out now.
我不會丟下傑克
I'm not leaving Jack.
不用管我 跟他走
Don't worry about me, go with him.
快走
Get out of here.
把門打開
Unlock this door.
聽著 我幫不了傑克 我只能幫你
Look, I can't help Jack, I can only help you.
你不能丟下傑克
You are not leaving Jack.
我特麼就是幹這個的 混蛋
I'm getting paid, motherfucker.
傑克 傑克 你在麼 小夥伴
Jack, oh Jack, you out there, son?
聽著我有話要澄清 哥們
Listen I got a confession to make, pal.
你妻子在我耳邊悄悄說
Your wife whispered in my ear
她想和我共度良宵
that she wants to suck my dick.
你喜歡嗎
You like that?
我和你做個交易
I'll make you a deal.
你把屬於我的東西給我 我就放過你
You give me what's mine and I'll let you go.
不應該是這樣的 傑克
It wasn't supposed to be like this, Jack.
是嗎
Oh yeah?
應該是怎樣的
How was it supposed to be?
你殺了我們然後拿走債券
You kill us and take the bonds?
你說對了
You got it.
嘿 出去把他幹掉
Hey, get the fuck out there.
幹得漂亮 傑克
Nice shot, Jack.
可惜不是我
Too bad it wasn't me.
聽著 去他媽的貝克爾
Listen, fuck Beeker.
憑什麼他應該拿錢
Why should he get the money?
我和你 我們平分這筆錢
Me and you, we split the money, 50/50.
聽起來怎麼樣
How's that sound?
聽起來完全是胡扯
Sounds like bullshit.
傑克
Hey Jack.
殺了你以後 我就上了你女人
After I kill you, I'm gonna fuck that little whore of yours.
你現在可以不和我合作
You keep what's mine.
該死
Oh shit.
你聽到了嗎
You hear that?
我們都會進監獄的
We're both gonna go to fucking prison.
你不會
You wouldn't, uh,
你不會在人背後開槍的 對吧
you wouldn't shoot a man in the back, would you?
不 我會的
Yes, I would.
槍 他有槍
Gun, he's got a gun.
天哪 我們這有緊急情況
Geez, we got a situation here.
請求增援
Call for backup.
瑪格麗特 再別提了
Margaret, don't bring it up again.
告訴那些傢伙車庫有一個梯子
Just tell the guys there's a ladder in the garage,
或者我們租他們的 因為他們收你租金
or we'll rent theirs, 'cause they'll charge you rent.
讓他們爬到屋頂上
And have them climb up on the roof
別告訴他們我們沒有保險
and don't tell 'em we don't have insurance.
不 我現在不打算和你探討這個
No, I'm not gonna discuss it with you now,
我回家後再說
I'll do it when I get home.
獄長
Warden.
-你好嗎先生 -我很好
- How're you, sir? - I'm fine.
謝謝你為客戶的服務
Thank you for your service to your client.
但現在沒你的事了
But you are done here, sir.
謝謝
Thank you.
我喜歡律師這個詞 我一直都很喜歡
- I love the word barrister, I always have.
等你成了法官後
And you have the best job in America,
你就有全美國最好的工作
when you become a judge.
因為你每天上班都有
Because every day you get to go to work
評判公正的機會
with a chance to be fair.
-再次謝謝你 獄長 -過得愉快先生
- Thanks again, Warden. - Good day, sir.
看 這是我工作的一部分
See, it's part of my job.
你的工作是成為蜘蛛俠
And your job is trying to be Spiderman
爬上二樓做壞事
and climb up to second stories and do bad things.
然後你就被抓了
And you got caught.
你要溫水還是涼水
Would you rather have the water warmer or colder?
脫衣服
Strip.
正面
Full frontal.
非常好 你做的很好
Very good, you'll do.
你用不著遮遮掩掩的 夥計
You don't need to cover it, bud,
不論你有什麼我們都不會驚訝的
we couldn't be shocked by anything you'd have.
-你好啊 小伙子 -先生
Hello son. Sir.
-今天過得怎麼樣先生 -很好先生
- How're you today, sir? - Good, sir.
好
Good.
你呢
How about you?
準備好離開這了
About ready to get out of here.
非常好 先生
Very good, sir.
嘿
HEY
好吧 不管用
Well, that didn't work.
也許你只是沒禮貌
Maybe you're just rude.
你不懂禮節
You don't have manners.
當有比你年長者站在你牢門外的時候
When one of your betters is outside and front of the bars,
你站起來 轉過身
you stand up, turn around,
直視他的眼睛
and look him in the goddamned eye.
差不多就是這樣
That's more like it.
你知道我需要你幹什麼嗎
You know what I need from you?
你的注意力
Your attention.
並且是每一次我關注你的時候
And I'm gonna demand it
你都要關注我
every time I look in your fucking eyes.
我們的牢房還不錯吧
How're you enjoying our fine facility?
我希望能達到你的標準
I hope it's up to your standards.
你喜歡嗎
Is it to your liking?
或者說你看到更好的了
Or have you seen better?
又或者說你更喜歡在地下的洞裏
Or would you rather be in a hole underground?
你聽見了嗎
Can you hear me?!
因為你聽我說話很重要
Because it's important you hear me.
每次我看到你的臉
Every time I've ever looked in your face,
即使是在我的辦公室
even back in my office,
你從都是對我目不轉睛
you never took your eyes off me.
我可沒那麼大的魅力 小伙子
I'm not that fucking attractive, bud.
你經常給我這種黃金凝視
You always give me that gold stare,
這他媽根本不管用 你永遠都嚇不了我
it don't mean shit to me, you're not gonna scare me down.
你明白了嗎
You understand that, don't you?
我才不管你認為自己有多壞
I don't care how bad you think you are.
你不會和劊子手一樣壞
You're not as bad as the executioner.
嘿 咸魚
Hey, fish.
能明白我的娛樂方式嗎
Got my jollies?
你知道這發生了什麼嗎
Do you know what's happening here?
你知道發生什麼了嗎
You know what's happening?
-滾開 -撿肥皂呢 小子
- Fuck off. - Party, motherfucker.
一個盛大的派對
A big party.
到這裏來
Get over here.
我要爆你菊花 漂亮的男孩
I'm gonna skullfuck you, pretty boy.
來自獄長的小禮物
A little present from the Warden.
棒極了 這就是贏定了
Hell yeah, that's what's up.
你這特麼的是什麼
What the fuck are you?
還記得我嗎 混球
Remember me, motherfucker?
你壞事做盡 小伙子
You've been up to a lot of bad shit, son.
為什麼我要留下
Why do I stay?
我留下是因為我喜歡壞人
You know what I stay, 'cause I like bad guys.
因為他們不想成為壞人
Because they don't wanna be bad guys.
他們都認為我們是壞人
And a lot of 'em think we're the bad guys,
我是個壞人
and I'm a bad guy.
我喜歡罪犯 他們很敬業
And I like criminals, professionals at what they do.
我尤其喜歡二樓的那個
I particularly like the second story man,
因為他很健壯 動作敏捷
'cause he's gotta be athletic, he's gotta be agile.
他很有想法
He's gotta think.
你把這些足智多謀的人聚集在一起
You put all that ingenuity together,
你只是在想 我們為什麼不能好好相處呢
and you wonder, why can't we all just get along?
你想表達啥 獄長
What's your proposition, Warden?
你知道罪犯和執法者之間的
You know the difference between a criminal,
區別嗎
and a law man?
第一
One,
住所免費 免費三餐供應 免費住宿
lives rent free, three meals a day, a bed.
另一個呢
The other one,
連租金都付不起
can't even pay his rent.
我們那位東海岸的"叔叔"
And our uncle, who lives back there on the east coast,
不會給我這樣的人付錢
doesn't pay people like me shit.
現在我在考慮不久後的退休
Now I'm thinking of retiring soon.
我有三個女兒
And I got three daughters.
所以你掂量一下
So you do the math.
你知道騙子和執法者之間
You know what the real difference
真正的區別嗎獄長
is between crooks and law men is, Warden?
告訴我
Try me.
是在牢門的哪一邊
What side of the bars they're on.
很聰明
That's clever.
你這樣的覺悟
With a mind like that,
不應該被關在這樣的地方
you should be nowhere near an institution like this.
你願意餘生都在這裏渡過嗎
You wanna stay here the rest of your life?
還是你想出去
Or you wanna be out there?
你想讓你的妹子圍著
You want your girl running around,
監獄跑圈嗎 她是那樣的姑娘嗎
outside the walls of this prison, looking like she does?
沒有監管
Without supervision?
我認為不是
I don't think so.
現在 你更想留在這裏還是出去
Now, in your own mind, are you better in or out?
因為這正是我們所討論的
Because that's what we're talking about.
我們做筆交易 然後你想去哪都可以
So let's make a deal, and you can take a hike,
我也不會再做那個討人厭的獄長
and I can quit being a fucking warden.
如果你打算和我做這個交易
If you're gonna make a deal with me,
你就和我握手
you're gonna shake my hand.
成交
Deal.
獄長的觀點很簡單
The Warden's proposition was simple.
一些告密者洩露的情報
Some snitch had let it slip
邊境地帶會有一次毒品交易
that a drug deal was going down by the border.
讓我去拿現金 他就是乾淨的
Having me get the cash kept his hands clean.
作為回報 我可以離開監獄
And in return, I got a get outta jail free card
一個新的身份 人生的第二次機會
with a new identity, and a second chance at life.
而且我很幸運
And lucky for me,
有個善良的女人在身後等我
there was a good hearted woman waiting.
你還好嗎
You okay?
你不必這麼做的
You don't have to do this.
我們可以離開這裏 重新開始
We can go away, start again.
不管在哪我們都只能幹這行
We'll just have to do it someplace else.
-獄長 -說
- Warden. - Yeah.
我們到了 正在停車
Yeah, we're here, we're packing in.
交易結束前把他看住了
Just stay with him until the deal's done.
你明白了嗎
You understand that, right?
明白
Got it.
小子 你的槍法最好有你自己說的那麼好
You better be the shot you say you are, boy.
我什麼都看不到
I can't see a goddamn thing.
準備好擴音器
Get ready with the bullhorn.
只要你們按我說的做
No one else needs to get hurt.
你們的命就可以保住
You just do exactly what I say.
放下槍 把鑰匙丟掉 然後走開
Drop your guns, throw your keys, and keep walking.
一直走 不要回頭
Walk away and don't look back.
你只殺了兩個 混賬東西
You only killed two, goddamn it.
沒必要殺剩下那兩個人
There's no need to kill the rest.
我來定生死 別忘記你只是個犯人
I'll say what is needed, convict.
約定裏沒說要把毒品帶回去
Drugs weren't part of the deal.
是你的約定 不是我們的
Your deal, not ours.
-幹嘛 -獄長
- Yeah. - Warden.
他們住進了 你讓他們去的汽車旅館
They checked into the motel you got 'em.
很好
That's good.
你知道這事是怎樣的
You know what the story is.
是
Yeah.
你知道你應該幹什麼吧
You know what you have to do.
-明白了嗎 -明白
Got it? - Copy that.
獄長的人拿了那些毒品
Warden's man took the drugs,
但我手上拿著那些錢
but I held onto the money.
明早他會在旅館跟我見面
He'd meet me at the hotel in the morning,
我會用這些錢換我的新生活
and I'd exchange his money for my new life.
早上我們把這些錢給莫頓
In the morning we'll just give this money to Morton.
一切就結束了
And we're done.
我不確定
I don't know.
這事總感覺不對勁
This whole thing feels off.
你保證 這是最後一次了
Promise me, this is the last one.
我不能失去你
I can't lose you.
我答應 但有一個條件
On one condition.
你願意和我度過佘生嗎
Will you spend the rest of your life with me?
我願意
Yes.
戴上看看
Try it on.
很合適
It fits.
你覺得它怎麼樣
What do you think?
它很美
It's beautiful.
在光線下看起來怎麼樣
Tell me how it looks in the light.
閃閃發光
It sparkles.
像你的眼睛一樣閃閃發光
It sparkles like your eyes.
-我很喜歡 -希望如此
- I love it. - I hope so.
你把我慣壞了
You spoiled me.
這一切結束後 等我們有足夠的錢
When all this is done, we'll have enough money.
我們就重新開始
We'll start over again.
有個家 生兩個兒子
We're gonna have a house, maybe two baby boys.
我真的會金盆洗手的
I'll even retire, you know,
去當個郵遞員 做做普通人的工作
be a postman like a regular old job or something.
只要能每天在你身邊醒來
Just to be able to wake up every morning next to you.
你覺得怎樣 親愛的
What do you think about that, babe?
我好愛你
I love you so much.
我也愛你
I'm glad you do.
謝謝你 寶貝
Thank you, baby.
寶貝 趴下
Baby, get down.
快 去抓他
Go on, get him.
寶貝
. Baby
沒事的
It's okay.
不不 寶貝 你不會有事的 沒事的
No no, babe, no you're okay, you're okay.
你沒事的 你會好起來的
You're okay, hey, you're gonna be okay.
奧利維亞
Olivia.
求求你 不要睡過去
Please stay awake.
再堅持一會就好
Just a little longer,
我們馬上就有個家了 我答應過你的
we're gonna get that house I promised you.
好嗎
Okay.
我們還有很多事要做
We got a lot left to do.
我愛你 傑克
I love you, Jack.
奧利維亞
Olivia.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
奧利維亞
Olivia.
求你了
Please.
嘀
Tick.
嘀嗒
Tick tock.
嘀
Tick.
嗒
Tock.
嘀
Tick.
嗒
Tock.
事情就是這樣
And so it goes.
這很好
This was good.
今天有進展
This was a lot of progress.
然後
And,
明天我們討論一下你潛在的
tomorrow we'll get to the underlying--
明天我要見一個真正的醫生
Tomorrow I have a date with a real doctor.
你知道最糟糕的是什麼嗎
You know what the worst part is?
沒人會為我送別
Nobody's gonna be there to see me off.
無論如何
Anyway
跟你談話很愉快 阿曼達
It was nice talking with you, Amanda.
我也是 傑克
You too, Jack.
我告訴你 他就是個該死的混蛋
I am telling you, he's one nasty son of a bitch.
他僱用年輕人 比競爭者們付更多的錢
He hires young, he pays more than all his competitors,
等他把他們弄到手了 就不會放手
and when he gets his hooks in 'em, he doesn't let go.
監察他所有的分析師
Check all his analysts.
監視他戰壕裏的狐朋狗友們
Even his guys down there in the trenches,
他們肯定會有所動作的
they're bound to make a mistake.
當他們行動時 我們會等著
And when they do, we will be ready.
讓他們在自投羅網
We will be ready.
-幹得不錯 卡特賴特先生 -謝謝
Good work, Mr. Cartwright. - Thank you.
真的不錯
Good work.
吉爾 我得跟她聊聊
Jill, give us a minute.
-好的 沒問題 -謝謝
- Yeah sure, no problem. - Thank you.
泰勒醫生
Dr. Tyler.
-這是給你的 -這是什麼
- There you go. - What do you got for me?
-你在逗我 -我很認真
You can't be serious. - I'm serious.
德克薩斯對約翰遜
Texas versus Johnson.
好吧
Okay.
醫生 你說你想拯救人的性命
You claim you wanna save lives, Doctor.
你宣揚為了正義而奮鬥
You preach fighting the good fight.
你在講堂裏宣揚所謂的正義
You wave your flag of justice around your lecture hall
就像復仇的天使一般
like some avenging angel.
但這個
But this?
這不是病例研究
This is not a case study.
這也不是著書立說 弘揚道理 粉飾太平
This is not about theorizing, glorifying, or grandstanding.
泰勒醫生 這是因果報應
Dr. Tyler, this is about paying a debt.
這不僅是欠受害者家人的債
It's not just a debt to the families of the victims,
也是欠給社會的債 這才是正義
but to society, righting a terrible wrong,
防止以後再犯這樣的錯
and preventing future wrongs.
是保護那些無辜者
Protecting the innocent.
在所有人之中 你應當是最能理解的
And you, of all people, should understand that
因為你的丈夫是被謀殺的
since your husband was murdered.
我說得對嗎
Am I correct?
你說得沒錯
Yeah, you're correct.
我的丈夫的確是被謀殺的
My husband was murdered.
那我現在問你一個問題
So let me ask you a question.
說
Shoot.
要是這一次 持續這個惡性循環
What if this time, perpetuating the cycle
繼續往錯的方向走
and continuing down the wrong path,
保護一個本就殘缺的體系
and protecting a broken system,
就是對社會最有效的幫助
isn't what's best for society?
我們的系統非常完整 醫生
System's far from broken, Doctor.
我們現在所延續的
We're traveling down a path humanity's been navigating
就是人類建立社會文明的根本
since the dawn of society.
法律和秩序
Law and order.
犯罪與懲罰
Crime and punishment.
以牙還牙
Tit for tat.
沒了這個體系
Without this system in place, we will surely
所有都要時刻保持警惕
be living in a constant state of hypersensitivity.
難道不是嗎
Wouldn't you say?
並不是的 人類已經向更高的階段發展了
No, we've moved beyond that.
人類早就過了靠原始本能反應的階段了
We are past reacting off of just our primal instinct.
我們現在處於更高等的階段了
We've moved beyond.
好吧 醫生 好吧
Okay, Doc. Okay.
看看你正在和誰說話
Look who you're talking to here.
那麼 你告訴我
You're gonna sit here and tell me this.
儘管他是個西裝革履受過良好教育的黑人
Even though an educated black man in a three piece suit
然而在德克薩斯
right here in the good state of Texas
依然沒法在不被人誤以為是罪犯的情況下
can't run down the street
走在街上
without possibly being mistaken for a criminal
或者像隻狗一樣被一槍打死
and shot down like a dog?
這代表著人類的進化嗎
That we have evolved.
這點我不敢茍同
I'd have to argue against that, Doctor.
這是一種微妙的平衡
It's a delicate balance.
懲罰太過嚴厲 就有反抗
Punish too harshly, you have a revolt.
懲罰不夠 社會就會動盪
Don't punish enough, you have anarchy.
對暴力的恐懼才能制約暴力
See, the very fear of violence keeps violence at bay.
我們要做的不是以暴制暴
By not responding to violence with violence,
如果我們消除了對暴力的恐懼
we take away that fear,
我們便毀了
and we take away the very thing
唯一能讓這個社會安定的因素
that keeps our system intact.
所以 醫生 我們的體系不是殘缺的
So no, Doctor, our system is not broken,
我們沒有走錯路
we are not headed down the wrong path.
我在為這個社會盡責
I'm doing my job for society.
而你卻不見得是在這麼做
Whether you are or not is yet to be seen.
那麼同情與憐憫呢
What about compassion and empathy?
仁慈呢
And mercy?
仁慈
Mercy.
我們都只是棋盤上的棋子 醫生
We're all just pieces on the board, Doctor.
我們都只是棋子
We're just pieces on the board.
是嗎 那棋局最後
Yeah, well, at the end of the game,
國王和小兵都會被放到同一個盒子裏
the king and the pawns go in the same damn box.
你不想幫我
You don't wanna help me?
那我就自己把這個送到州長那兒去
I'll take it to the Governor myself.
到時間了
Time to go.
我經過 那幽溪山谷
Yea, though I walk through
死亡的影子鋪陳其上
the valley of the shadow of death,
我不畏魔鬼 因你在身旁
I will fear no evil, for thou art with me.
你的棍杖 來撫慰我的心
Thy rod and thy staff, they comfort me,
再難言 仁慈與善良
surely the goodness of mercy
它們追隨至我生命盡頭
shall follow me all the days of my life.
我將終日憩息在主的蔭蔽下
And I will dwell in the house of the Lord forever.
有什麼遺言嗎 謝伊
Any last words, Shea?
最糟糕的是
he worst part is,
沒人會來為我送行
nobody's gonna be there to see me off.
拒絕簽特赦令
*
我愛你
I love you.
你很快就和我在一起了
I'll see you soon.
暴力
Violence.
由什麼引起的
What is the cause?
要真正的瞭解暴力的本質
To truly understand the nature of violence,
我們要超越個體地去看待它
we need to look beyond the individual.
我們要去瞭解
We need to look at the culture of violence
滲透進我們社會的 暴力文化
that permeates our society.
我們同樣也需要瞭解
And we also need to look at the way
暴力的懲罰方式
that we punish those that commit acts of violence.
因為當我們以暴制暴
Because when we answer violence with violence
殺人償命的時候
and trade death for death,
我們只是在加重惡性循環
all we're doing is perpetuating a vicious cycle.
但假如你愛的人被謀殺了呢
But what if someone you love was murdered?
你會認為
Would you feel that answering
以暴制暴才是正確的事嗎
violence with violence is appropriate?
我相信在那一瞬間我會有這種想法
I believe I would feel that in the moment.
但我不希望他們的死
But I wouldn't want their deaths avenged
在一個殘忍而無常的體系裏 得到復仇
by a cruel and capricious system.